<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on hurtling through space</title>
    <link>https://saisneha.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on hurtling through space</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>blogging@saisneha.com (Sneha S)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>blogging@saisneha.com (Sneha S)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 12:27:24 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://saisneha.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VHoIP #2 - July 2024</title>
      <link>https://saisneha.com/2024/07/vhoip2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 12:27:24 +0530</pubDate><author>blogging@saisneha.com (Sneha S)</author>
      <guid>https://saisneha.com/2024/07/vhoip2/</guid>
      <description>Thursday - 2020-07-18 Woke up at 5:50 AM. Had slept at 10:30 the night before - but was in bed by 9:45. That helped. Absolutely obliterated the partner at Othello. He declared me too competitive. Exercise. Hair wash day! Smoothie for breakfast. Thanks to SSJ for the suggestion. Game changing! Wearing all black to work. Interesting look! Work is chaotic. Too much to do! Need to hone down and focus. Trying our Morgen - alt to Akiflow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Voices in my Head over an Internet Protocol - VHoIP #1</title>
      <link>https://saisneha.com/2024/07/vhoip-1-the-voices-in-my-head-over-an-ip-week-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>blogging@saisneha.com (Sneha S)</author>
      <guid>https://saisneha.com/2024/07/vhoip-1-the-voices-in-my-head-over-an-ip-week-of/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to have a way to just jot down the various voices running through my head - perhaps it would be of some use to whoever else stumbles upon this.&#xA;Sunday - Wednesday (14 -17 July 2024) - Quick, non-detailed Recap Met friends on Sunday, spent time with partner in the morning. Slow day. Good day. Monday - Wednesday was spent working on a few things at work - a bit of firefighting and a bit of prioritising for the coming days.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrating my Mail and Cloud (De-Faanging my Life Ep #2)</title>
      <link>https://saisneha.com/2024/07/migrating-my-mail-and-cloud-de-faanging-my-life-ep-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 17:02:16 +0530</pubDate><author>blogging@saisneha.com (Sneha S)</author>
      <guid>https://saisneha.com/2024/07/migrating-my-mail-and-cloud-de-faanging-my-life-ep-2/</guid>
      <description>So, as I explained two weeks back, I&amp;rsquo;m making a concerted effort to move away from the big tech giants - opting for smaller, privacy centric options. This week, I&amp;rsquo;m going to document my journey there in a few key areas - Mail, Calendar, Meetings, and Cloud storage. I will be rambling quite a bit.&#xA;Before I get started, a colleague shared a very interesting article about the energy all our data consumes, comparing making an instagram post or tweet to switching on a light bulb that will never switch off.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De-FAANGing and De-googling my Life Ep #1: Framework and Dragons</title>
      <link>https://saisneha.com/2024/06/de-faanging-and-de-googling-my-life-ep-1-framework-and-dragons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>blogging@saisneha.com (Sneha S)</author>
      <guid>https://saisneha.com/2024/06/de-faanging-and-de-googling-my-life-ep-1-framework-and-dragons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve experimented with various online services, free and paid, and explored their feature sets, advantages, and disadvantages. In recent months, I have come to the difficult conclusion that my set up, honed over the past many years, is not only sub-optimal, but is also waiting to break. I&amp;rsquo;ve also realised that there is a great deal of dependency on Google, Apple, Microsoft, and other similar large tech companies, a group of corporations that used to, very aptly, be referred to as &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Tech&#34; title=&#34;Big Tech&#34;&gt;FAANG&lt;/a&gt;. I now wish to remedy this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isn&#39;t Sex just as socially constructed as Gender is, if not more?</title>
      <link>https://saisneha.com/2023/05/sex_and_gender_are_socially_constructed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><author>blogging@saisneha.com (Sneha S)</author>
      <guid>https://saisneha.com/2023/05/sex_and_gender_are_socially_constructed/</guid>
      <description>My team and I were recently on call with a public sector partner, where we’re constructing a dashboard to display disease dynamics. Among other things, one thing the dashboard did was it allowed you to filter disease incidence by sex. During the call, one of the members of our partner’s team said that she wanted us to change sex to gender in the filter.&#xA;Photo by Cecilie Johnsen on Unsplash</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Agony and The Ecstasy</title>
      <link>https://saisneha.com/2023/04/the_agony_and_the_ecstasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><author>blogging@saisneha.com (Sneha S)</author>
      <guid>https://saisneha.com/2023/04/the_agony_and_the_ecstasy/</guid>
      <description>This is a follow-up to the piece that inspired the title of this blog - Hurtling Through Space&#xA;It’s always an experience to stare at the night sky and feel it be so far away,&#xA;feel its vast nothingness, with specs of gas giants in between.&#xA;Perhaps an infinitesimal number of goldilocks rocks sustaining life?&#xA;We may never know- Oh the Agony, Oh the Ecstasy.&#xA;There is beauty and despair in the stars, a superimposition so beautifully tragic,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurtling through Space</title>
      <link>https://saisneha.com/2022/01/hurtling_through_space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><author>blogging@saisneha.com (Sneha S)</author>
      <guid>https://saisneha.com/2022/01/hurtling_through_space/</guid>
      <description>There is a place above the atmosphere of the earth, where stars and satellites live.&#xA;It is a large void, with sparse images being transmitted from the distant past.&#xA;We live on a rock in this void, a rock we call the Earth,&#xA;Hurtling through this void at speeds uncomprehendingly large.&#xA;As I zoom into our lives in this terrifyingly large yet beautiful contraption we call the universe, I have more questions than answers.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
